[ Tapping ]
- [ Pennywhistle Blows , Crowd Applauds ] - [ Man ] It 's Peeping Toms !
Starring Ted Craft . And now , here 's Ted !
Hello , everybody , and welcome to Peeping Toms ,
New York 's newest and grooviest game .
You have just seen the first half ...
of our real-life candid situation .
Now , in one minute , you will have to predict ...
just what our unsuspecting subject will do .
You folks there in the audience , and those of you peeking in at home ,
- guess along with us , okay ? All right . [ Laughter ]
Now , today , our Peeping Tom 's problem is , chivalry .
What does a fella do when a pretty girl ...
starts taking off all her clothes right there in front of him ?
- [ Hoots , Laughter ] - A blind girl , that is .
Lovely young model Danielle Breton ...
agreed to be our decoy .
Now , Danielle is not really blind ,
but that 's what we want our male friend to think .
Okay , peepers , look at the board .
You 've got 20 seconds to pick your answer .
[ Pennywhistle Blows , Metronome Ticks ]
[ Pennywhistle Blows ]
[ Craft Reads List ]
- [ Springing ] - [ Springing ]
- [ Craft ] Well , look at that ! - [ Beeping ]
Both of our contestants have picked the same answer .
- Let 's see if they 're right .. - [ Pennywhistle Blows ]
[ Pennywhistle Blows , Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Craft ] Oh , I am sorry , Pat and Fred , but better luck next time .
- Right , audience ? - [ Applause ]
All right . And now , before we meet our contestants for tomorrow ,
let 's bring out the lovely Danielle Breton , our blind girl .
♪ ♪ [ Organ jingle ]
- Bravo , Danielle . - Thank you .
It 's so nice to see you . Danielle , what do you do in real life ?
[ French Accent ] Right now I study to be a model with Gene Fox ,
and also I study to be an actress .
Great ! That 's wonderful , Danielle .
Danielle , let 's bring out our other guest ,
Peeping Tom 's own Mr. Chivalry ,
- Philip Woode . - [ Applause ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Organ ] - Hello , Phil . Nice to meet you .
You 're a great sport .
Phil , what do you do in real life ?
I 'm an advertising manager for The Amsterdam Star .
Oh , great . That 's wonderful .
- ♪ ♪ [ Organ ] - I 'm glad to ... Oh ! Uh-oh .
It 's been wonderful talking with you , Danielle and Phil ,
but that music tells us that we just have time to give away our prizes ...
before we have to say bye-bye .
Danielle , for you , this complete set of Reynolds stainless steel cutlery .
- Thank you . - Ha , ha . Congratulations .
And Phil , for you , good sport that you are ,
dining and dancing for two ...
at Manhattan 's famous African Room .
[ Applause ]
Philip !
l just remembered that I haven 't eaten all day ...
and I thought maybe you want some help with your dinner for two .
I don 't bite , you know .
That is , if I 'm filled I don 't bite .
I-I have brought my own cutlery .
[ Laughs ]
- All right , let 's go get my car . - Okay .
♪ ♪ [ Rhythmic , Mid-Tempo Jazz ]
[ Elephant Trumpets ]
[ Danielle ] I don 't know what to do , so I just stand there ...
and , uh , I feel very stupid and about , uh ...
Then I said to the photographer ...
I said something so terrible you can 't even put it in the French movie .
But he deserved that , you know .
He 's a ... How you say that word ?
He 's a son of a bastard .
- Son of a bitch . - Yes , he was that too . Son of a bitch .
But I 'm not , you know , I 'm not like you Americans ' women 's liberation .
I don 't , uh , I don 't spend my life to hate the men .
I don 't like that , but this man , he have deserve what I tell him .
So , after that have happen to me , then , uh ,
I said to myself , " Now it 's time for you to go from Quebec . "
- Quebec ? - Yes .
- I thought you were French . - Oh , yes , I 'm French-Canadian .
It 's not the same , you know .
Quebec is very pretty , you know , but now , for me ,
New York is the home . Is for me ... is for me , freedom , New York .
Yesterday you know what I have do ?
I go to the top of the Empire State Building .
You know , the ... that building , the big ...
And I am up there by myself , and nobody know I am there .
I look down , I can see all the little car and the people ,
and I 'm all by myself , and nobody knows that I 'm there .
Do you like to be alone ?
Sometime I do , but not tonight .
[ French Accent ] Danielle , I think I should take you home now .
I 'm sorry . This is so embarrassing .
I waited for you at the TV studio . You saw me .
Why can 't you leave me alone ?
Look here , Miss Breton and I were just having a drink .
Mrs. Emil Breton and you .
I am not married ! I have been divorced for a year .
- But still he follows me . - Danielle , that is quite enough .
We do not want to discuss our very private problems in front of strangers .
- Come along now . - Don 't touch me !
- Waiter ? - I will go , but not with you .
- It is important we go home now . - Yes , sir ?
This gentleman is bothering us .
You better come with me , sir .
- Just come with me . - Danielle . Danielle !
Come home with me !
Danielle ! Get your hands off me !
Come on . Uh , I better take you home .
- Okay . - Where do you live ?
- Staten Island . - Staten Island ?
I thought you said you lived in New York .
Isn 't Staten Island in New York ?
I guess it is . Come on .
You know , there are so few people ...
that I have any feeling for .
Not just men , you know .
Ever since my sister left .
We have had such a close bond .
Hey . Hey !
[ Fog Horn Blows ]
Oops !
[ Sighing ]
Well , here is my apartment .
I have just move in , you know . I have a dishwasher .
[ Laughing ] A real dishwasher ?
♪ [ Humming ]
- Ah . - [ Giggles ]
I think it 's very hot right here .
[ Laughing ] I think I 'll turn the thermostat down .
[ Mumbling ]
Philip , you know I think what you should do ?
Ooh ! You just must wait there for me .
[ Continues . Indistinct ]
Oh , Christ .
Philip , what are you doing ?
Does your ex-husband make a habit ...
of standing guard out there ?
Why he is always following me ?
What is so terrible , you know , is his persistence .
He-He says that we can work it through ,
but I don 't want to work it through .
Some time there are no solution .
I think you better go .
- Wait . Wait , look . I got an idea . - No , I think ...
- What ? - Why don 't I go downstairs .
I 'll get in the car . I 'll drive around the block .
And I 'll park . And then I 'll come back through the back entrance .
I 'll pretend to leave .
Okay ?
- I don 't know if that 's such a good idea to do . - Trust me .
I got rid of him before . I can do it again .
- Okay . - I 'll be right back .
I 'll wait for you .
[ Car Door Closes ]
[ Engine Starts ]
You forgot your cutlery .
[ Danielle Moaning ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Woman ] Danielle .
Danielle !
[ Danielle Speaking French ]
[ Woman Speaking French ]
- Oh , excuse me . - Oh , say ...
Shh , shh , shh .
- Who was that ? Who was that ? - It is my sister .
Come on , take it easy . You can tell me .
She 's so crazy . She get ...
She get so angry with me when I 'm with anyone ,
except for her , my husband and now you .
Why is she here ?
[ Sniffles , Sighs ]
Because we are twins and today is our birthday ...
and she can come visit me but she know that she have to go back ...
and so ... [ Sighs ] and so she feel very bad .
- Look , why don 't I leave . - No , no , no ! Please ?
- Stay with me . - Okay .
I look so terrible , I think .
- No . - I have such a headache .
- I have had too much hflanhattans last night . - A little .
Philip , I think I would feel better .
I have no more of these pills .
- Could you get me some at the drug store ? - Sure .
- You know where is Bay Street ? - Yeah .
And then we have a happy birthday together .
$ 4.50 .
$ .79 , $ .89 , $ 1.29 .
That 's $ 7.68 .
- Yes . - [ Emil ] You must do as I tell you .
- Yes , I ... - You are not well .
Yes , I know . Please , but I have only ...
I have only two pills left . Please hurry .
Yeah , that one 's fine . And I 'd like something written on it .
Can 't have it . The cake decorator isn 't in yet .
- Well , couldn 't you do it ? - Are you kidding ?
- Well , why not ? - Hey , Louise , he wants me to write on a cake .
- You ? I 'd like to see you try . - Mm-hmm .
All right then , I will . What do you want written ?
Happy birthday to Danielle ... No . Uh ...
Happy birthday to Dominique and Danielle .
Dominique and Danielle . You gotta be kidding .
Come on . Let me show you .
[ Moans ]
[ Panting , Moaning ]
Surprise .
Hey , now you know you 're not supposed to cut the cake ...
until you make a wish and blow out the candles .
[ Philip Screaming ] No !
[ Screaming ]
[ Dial Tone ]
Hello ? I want to report an emergency ... a murder .
Hello . I want to report a murder .
A man , about 25 , black .
I saw it just now through my window .
I live in the apartment just across the courtyard . 36 Hamilton .
Yes . I 'll meet you downstairs right away . My name is Grace Collier .
Yes , the Grace Collier . I wrote that story .
[ Knock At Door ] - I 'm sorry you feel that way , Detective ,
but I have to write it the way I see it .
Sometimes the police are wrong .
Look , this is ridiculous . We can 't discuss it now . A man is bleeding to death .
- [ Knocking Continues ] - Yeah. right away .
- [ Knocking Continues ] - I 'm coming , I 'm coming .
[ Danielle ] Dominique ?
[ Knocking Continues ]
- [ Knocking ] - Just a minute .
- What 's wrong ? - Oh , Emil , thank you for coming ,
but , uh , everything is fine now and I get dressed ...
- and go out ... - What happened ?
Well , this morning I felt those pains ...
What happened ?
[ Whispering ] Dominique . What have you done ?
Dominique is here ?
She was .
Watch out .
Someone might look in the window .
Help me .
Help me !
- Help me ! - Wh-What are you going to do ?
[ Man On Radio ] It 's a beautiful day here in New York .
This is Windy Craig on the radio for you .
[ Radio Continues , Indistinct ]
[ Grunts ]
On the couch .
[ Whimpers ]
[ Grunts ] Help me .
[ Gagging ]
[ Retching ]
Put on some makeup .
It must look as if nothing has happened .
- Drop it there . - I 'm Grace Collier .
I just spoke to you on the telephone .
How you doing , Miss Collier ? I 'm Detective Kelly .
My partner , Detective Spinetti .
- What seems to be the problem ? - You 're the man ...
I spoke to , aren 't you ?
- That 's right . - Well , I imagine we can discuss ...
I hope there 's not too much imagination involved here .
You obviously don 't think so , or you wouldn 't be here .
Now , I just saw a man viciously and repeatedly stabbed .
It was in that apartment up there ... 3-R . The name is Breton .
The man 's probably dying if he 's not dead already ,
so I think the best thing to do is to get up there .
All right , take it easy , will you , lady ?
These people are always stabbing each other .
- " These people " ? - All right , all right . Let 's just keep calm .
One step at a time .
Your story is that you looked out the window .
- What time would that have been ? - Your people have this written down .
The thing to do is to try to get up there ...
and try to save that poor guy .
Miss Collier , our work is a profession .
- A doctor , for example , doesn 't begin to operate ... - You 're not a doctor .
I read your article about police brutality in Stapleton .
And the next time The Staten Island Panorama decides to investigate ...
- our methods , I hope they send a real reporter . - I 'm going up there .
- And you 're certainly not a cop . - And you 're not either ...
if you don 't do something about this .
Unless , of course , you 'd rather go beat up a few students .
Ever hear of a search warrant , Miss Civil Liberties ?
Well , you haven 't got one , and neither do I.
You mean you 're actually gonna stand here and ask me idiotic questions ...
like some dumb courtroom drama while a man dies ?
I saw it . Saw it happen .
- Actually saw it happen . - Calm down , calm down .
Now , you just go back to your apartment and relax .
And watch you walk off ?
You 'd like that , wouldn 't you ?
That 'd make a great story for your next issue .
" Police refuse to investigate brutal race murder . "
Not a chance , lady . You stick with us .
And keep your mouth shut .
I 'll do what I consider necessary .
This isn 't a police state yet .
3-R is this way .
[ Doorbell Buzzing ]
- Yes ? - Police officer .
- Oh , yes ? Can I help you ? - Are you the lady of the house ?
- Yes , I am . - You live here alone ?
- Yes . - Had any company this morning ?
- Oh , no . - Two people ... - That will do , Miss Collier .
If there is some information that you need , I will be glad to help you ,
but as you can see , I am in the middle of dressing ,
so , uh , if you excuse me , I 'll finish .
- She 's afraid . - You mind ...
- You mind if we come in ? - just what do you want ?
If you don 't mind our coming in , this lady will explain .
Have you the search , um ... the search permission ? Have you that ?
- You mean a search warrant ? - Yes , the search warrant . Have you that ?
- No . - She 's stalling . She 's hiding the body .
If you have not the search warrant , it 's not very important .
So if you will excuse me , I finish to dress .
It 'll take me just ten minutes to get a search warrant ,
and while Spinetti here is going to the trouble of doing that ,
- I shall naturally have to ... - Excuse me .
I don 't mean to offend you . Come in .
But you know , I see all the time on the television show ...
the scene of the evil criminal and the policeman ,
and the policeman knock on the door ...
and the criminal , he ask about , you know ,
what you have ask me ... the search warrant .
But you have not said to me ,
" Open in the name of the law . " You have not said that .
- Now , then , Miss ... - Danielle . Danielle Breton .
I 'm Detective Kelly . This is Detective Spinetti ,
- How do you do ? - This is Miss Collier , your neighbor ...
- from across the way . - Hello . How are you ?
- Hello . - Something very unusual occurred this morning .
Seems that Miss Collier happened to glance out of her window ...
and saw something which so shocked and disturbed her ...
- that she called the police department . - I saw a murder .
Thank you , Miss Collier .
Now , then , Miss Breton , I suppose you can see ...
- Miss Collier 's apartment from here . - I really don 't know .
You know very well you can .
Yes , there 's my window . This is definitely the right apartment .
Miss Collier , do you spend a lot of time watching my apartment ?
You saw me . You know you did .
[ Laughs ] If , uh , I have seen you ,
then I would have pulled the shade and if I do that ,
I have to give up all my life ...
- to have the privacy . - She did draw the shade .
Obviously once she 'd hidden the body she felt safe .
But it must be here somewhere .
I can 't believe that this is serious .
He wrote " help " on this window in his own blood .
and I watched him write it .
- Here he write that ? - Naturally she washed it off .
It 's all so obvious . This girl is protecting someone .
But the murderess is someone this girl knows .
She was shorter and had a twisted face ...
and stringy hair and was having a terrible fit of some kind .
- You know someone who would fit that description , Miss Breton ? - No .
Good God ! I saw the knife ! I saw her stab him !
Could somebody have gotten in here without your knowledge ?
It would be impossible . I was here all morning .
What about the man that stayed over ?
I was quite alone .
You see , I 'm-I 'm divorced from my husband , and still , uh ...
Well , it 's very personal , you know .
But Miss Collier , many time at night I watch the television show ...
and I watch the horror film , and it make me full of fear ,
and-and I jump at every noise .
I understand that when you live alone it make you ... It 's very difficult .
I understand that .
What I saw happen was real .
Mind if we have a look around ?
No , it 's perfectly all right .
Thank you , Miss Collier .
I know you 're doing your best to help the forces of justice ,
but they will be better served by your sitting down .
That body is here somewhere ,
and she knows it .
[ Kelly ] How many rooms do you have , Miss Breton ?
Well , uh , there is the living room here ,
and then the bathroom and the kitchen
and then past is the bedroom .
You mind if we see the bathroom ?
No . The bathroom is here .
- See ? This . And , uh ... - Bedroom ?
Yes , the bed room is down here .
- In here . - Coming , Miss Collier ?
Oh , uh , ' scuse me for a second .
[ Others Speaking , Indistinctly ]
[ Toilet Flushes ]
[ Spinetti ] Miss Collier , would you stick with us , please ?
- I understand . - Have you looked under the bed ?
I was waiting for you .
Any luck ?
I think we should check those hallway closets .
- It 's fine with me . They are right here . - Thank you .
There you are ... and there .
- Can we look in these bags ? - Yes , fine .
[ Unzipping Bags ]
Why do you have things in pairs , like twins ?
- [ Laughs ] - You have a twin .
I have a television commercial to do some time ...
and in case I should get the makeup on the dress ,
then there is another one for the next take .
You see , uh , I 'm a model .
And some time an actress too .
- You certainly are . - That will do , Miss Collier .
I 'm sorry to have troubled you , Miss Breton .
- I 'm coming , I 'm coming . - I 'm sure you 'll report it to the police .
- Oh , yes . - By withholding evidence ,
you can make yourself an accessory after the fact .
[ Danielle ] If I do hear anything , I 'll telephone you .
- [ Doorbell Buzzes ] - Oh , excuse me .
- Oh ! - Hello , darling . Am I late ?
No . Officer Kelly , this is my , uh , husband ...
my ex-husband , Emil Breton , and Officer Spinetti .
[ Emil ] Now you have done something naughty and the police have found out .
[ Danielle ] No , they tell me that they look for a dead body .
[ Laughing ] Are you serious ?
[ Kelly ] Well , the lady claims she saw a murder victim .
- Mind if I ask you a few questions ? - No , not if I can help .
just what is your full name ?
- Emil Breton . - How long have you and Mrs. Breton been divorced ?
We are not divorced . We are separated .
Dominique and Danielle ! She does have a twin ! Oh !
It was right ... right here .
- Listen ... - Listen . One more word out of you and I 'm going to book you .
I 'll book you on something . I 'll find something in the book to book you on .
Attempted libel , assault on a police officer ...
I don 't care what it is , but I 'll do it .
I saw a murder , and I 'll prove it .
Listen , Miss Collier , I don 't know what kind of a nut you are ,
or what kind of an exposé you 're looking to get ,
but just don 't bother me or that girl upstairs , okay ?
Far as I 'm concerned , this case is closed , you got that ? Closed !
[ Car Starts ]
Grace , I thought we were supposed to meet upstairs .
What are you doing here ?
Grace , it 's Tuesday .
Oh , I forgot .
Um , well , let 's go .
Honey , don 't you think you ought to change into something a little bit more ...
Yeah , I 'll change . I 'll meet you at the car , okay ?
Honey , I thought we were going upstairs to have a little chat ,
and if you were embarrassed about the mess ,
you know I 'm always glad to help you tidy up .
Although , what you 're going to do when you get married , I don 't know .
Oh , did I tell you the Cunningham girl is engaged ?
She 's about your age , and she finally found somebody that suits her .
He 's a doctor .
Well , he 's a veterinarian , but the animals are all owned by wealthy people ...
And he has his own hospital .
So you see , honey ? just because things aren 't working out ...
with you and your editor ... Uh , what 's his name ? ... Jim ?
- I don 't want to discuss that . - Oh .
Well , I 'm not trying to interfere , honey .
But you know , this doctor has a very interesting young assistant .
Grace , that reminds me .
They 've started right in our neighborhood ,
and I don 't know whether the zoning laws are going to permit it .
And I just don 't know how they got away with it .
But three or four blocks away from us ... Are you listening , honey ?
Because this would make a very interesting story for your newspaper .
An experimental mad house .
Now , you see , what 's worse is that they just let them walk around .
The whole idea is that instead of locking them up ,
they let them live in a house ...
and the doctors make a home for them ,
and it 's sort of a family situation , just like real people .
It 's very advanced . I saw something about it on television .
Now you see , honey ? There are interesting things ...
going on right here on Staten Island .
But I tell you , I don 't feel safe at night .
- Would you stop here ? Pull over . - Why ?
Everything looks so ...
If you want pastry , let 's wait and get it at Brian 's .
I don ' t want any pastry .
Did a man come in here this morning and buy a birthday cake ?
Lady , ten men came in and bought ten birthday cakes .
This cake had two names on it , but written the way a child writes , not the way a ...
Oh , yeah . The colored guy that made me write on the cake .
- What were the names ? - I don 't know .
Daisy and Debbie .
Dominique and Danielle .
- That 's what it was . - Yeah ! That 's it .
I did it , and I don 't even remember .
- Can I have your names , please ? - What for ?
My name is Grace Collier , and I write for The Staten Island Panorama .
And I 'm her mother , Mrs. Payson Collier .
My girlfriend and I read your column .
My name is Elaine Deanna .
Deanna .
- And the other girl is Louise Wilanski . - Wilanski .
- What do you want to know ? - Thank you . That 's fine .
Huh . How do you like that ?
She says she 's gonna write an article , and she doesn 't ask us any questions .
They 're just terrible about deadlines .
Next , please ?
Really , Grace , you were rather abrupt .
I happen to be working on an assignment .
Well , don 't you think you 're taking this little job of yours a bit seriously ?
You 're 25 years old . You should be thinking about something else .
I 'm not gonna marry anybody .
And I wish you 'd stop referring to my work as " a little job . "
I like to call what I do a profession ,
only working for The Staten Island Panorama is a bit of a joke .
- Do you know what my next assignment is ? - No , I don 't .
I 'm having lunch tomorrow with an 80-year-old ex-con ...
who 's just carved an entire replica of the Danbury Penitentiary out of soap .
- Oh , that 's interesting . - Oh , I want to write about ...
about the apathy in the police force .
- About where the heroin goes after a bust . About the ... - Shh !
You don 't have to shout like you 're on the street .
What 's the matter with you ? I 've never seen you like this .
- I 'm on to something big . - Are you on diet pills again ?
I can see that you have your mind on other things .
- Can we have another date ? - We do have another date .
- You have supper with us on Friday . - Fine .
I 'll be there .
Well , can I drop you somewhere ?
No . It 's okay . I 'll walk .
Well , it 's not the way we planned it , but -
A white woman kills her black lover ,
and those racist cops couldn 't care less .
I saw it happen , and they won 't investigate .
Well , if you 're not interested ,
I 'm sure I can find someone else who 'd print it .
Lots of people would .
Good . You 're interested .
I 'll do my own investigation . Why not ?
I know more than those idiot police .
I know karate ... A private detective . Waste of money .
I ...
All right . All right , what 's his name ?
" Joseph Larch . "
- Now , I think the best thing for us to do ... - This is what we do .
You go up to your apartment , call Danielle , and see if anybody 's home .
If someone answers , wave once . If no one is there , wave twice .
- Well , you 're going up there if no one 's there ? - Sure .
All I have to do is know the situation in advance .
- I can play it either way . - Well , in that case , I can pretend ...
- to be making an informal telephone survey ... - You just do hand signals .
If there 's no one up there ,
I can charm the superintendent into giving me a passkey .
- No , you 've got to make a wax impression . - No one does that .
Go up to your apartment , watch the front while I 'm up there ,
and if you see someone coming , telephone the apartment .
- One ring . One ring and hang up . - Well , what if ...
- Does that answer your question ? - Yeah .
- But suppose that ... - Hey , have you ever been a detective ?
- No . - Have you ?
No , but simple logic suggests a way of doing things .
- I don 't see that it can be all that mysterious . - Grace , this is a craft .
I wouldn 't try to teach you how to write magazine articles .
Listen , I went to school to learn this ...
The Brooklyn Institute of Modern Investigation . Okay ?
- Okay . - Okay .
Now , you go on up to your apartment and do what I told you . Go ahead .
I 'll be here .
Larch ?
The boxes .
- What ? - Meet me in the truck .
My God .
Get out of there , Larch .
[ Telephone Rings ]
[ Grace Hangs Up ]
We got to get out of here .
[ Engine Starts ]
- What was that you were waving ? - I don 't know ,
but they had it hidden in the bedroom , so it might be something important .
Take a look in it while I tell you ...
about the real evidence I found in the living room .
I got up there without any trouble .
I did the usual search ... nothing .
I began to think that cop was right about you until I tried to move that couch .
- I couldn 't . It was too heavy . - The couch .
- Yeah . He 's in the couch . - What ?
- The body . - What about the body ?
What I went up there to look for , remember ?
The body is in the couch !
Terrific ! And the murderess is in here !
- What ? - Do you know what you 've found ?
A complete file on the Blanchion Twins .
- Now what are you talking about ? - Do you remember ...
about a year ago , Life magazine ran a whole story on them .
- The only Siamese twins ... - Look , I was up there , Grace ,
and I know what I know and saw , and I didn 't see no Siamese twins .
I do know that you have to have a dead body before you have a murder .
I gotta get going . We gotta catch this ferry .
You mean that 's all you 're gonna do ... locate the body and then split ?
- Yes , for Quebec . - Quebec ?
That 's where Breton told them to take it .
Now , wherever that couch goes , I follow , because somebody 's gonna be waiting for it ...
at the other end , and I want to know who .
- That makes sense . - Hey , lend me a dollar , will ya ?
When we get to Manhattan , I 'm gonna go see this writer ,
- and then ... - Then you go back to your apartment ,
lock the door , and wait for me to call . Period .
Where 's Arthur McLennen 's office ?
Uh , end of the hall , to your right .
- Uh , Miss , uh , Miss Collier ? - Yes .
Ah , yes . Well , I 'm , uh , I 'm Arthur McLennen .
- How do you do ? - Hello .
I , uh , I 'm afraid I 'm a little disorganized today .
Are , uh , are you here about , uh ...
- Well . That 's the Blanchion Twins file . - Yes , it is .
Now , I know you did the story over a year ago ,
but I was hoping you might remember enough about it to help me .
Oh , those poor girls .
You know , this looks like the file I saw at the Loisel Institute .
- Oh , it is the original , isn 't it ? - Yes , I believe it is .
How 'd you get it ? Are you going to do a follow-up ?
We never did . The managing editor would never assign it .
Well , they 've asked me to find out as much as I can about it .
We 're not quite sure what kind of a piece we 'd do .
Oh , well , come on in and we 'll talk about it , huh ?
The subject is a curious one .
After we ran this story , we got about 500 letters .
No matter what else they said , they all had that same tone of morbid fascination .
I don 't excuse myself , either .
Though I actually met the Blanchion girls , I was the same way .
Hey . You know , if you 're going to do that piece ,
I 've got something I 'd like to show you .
- Oh , I 'd appreciate anything that ... - You do have some time now ?
- Of course ! - Sometimes I forget myself when I get going on a subject ,
but actually , if you have the time , I 'd like to show you a videotape .
The more I learned , the more interested I became .
You see , to me at any rate , the psychological and philosophical elements ...
are of extreme importance .
Yes . Fine .
Well , there . About to begin .
[ Man Narrating ] Conjoined twins , called Siamese ,
challenge life at their first breath .
History had them as the stuff of myth and symbol .
Some tried to achieve such normality as they could .
The famous Chang and Eng , the twins of Siamese birth ...
who gave this congenital abnormality its popular name , .
married and fathered families .
Other twins lived by hiring themselves out to sideshows ...
or running small town souvenir shops .
With the sophisticated surgical techniques developed in this century ,
some twins have been separated and lead normal lives .
Others never can .
Born on March 27 , 1948 , in Quebec , the Blanchions ...
were Canada 's first Siamese twins .
Their parents died in an automobile accident only days before their first birthday .
Dominique and Danielle were to grow up ...
from then on within the pale walls of the Loisel Institute , .
where surgeons , reluctant to risk an operation on their delicate spinal conjoinment ,
decided to let them live as one .
- But Whether as twins through life ... - That 's Danielle 's husband .
- Who told you that ? - I want to hear this .
[ Narrator Continues ] There is always a price to pay .
It seems the older they become ,
the more precarious is their psychological balance ,
both within themselves and between one another .
In this , I am in agreement with my colleagues .
Although , they tend to think that Dominique ...
is the truly disturbed one ,
I think they will find that Danielle , who is so sweet ,
so responsive , so normal ,
as opposed to her sister ,
can only be so because of her sister .
- Bonjour , Dominique . - [ Speaking French ]
[ Narrator ] This was the last interview the conjoined twins would ever give .
That night , the doctors were forced by nature ...
to perform an operation they had hoped to avoid .
Late the next day , the institute announced the successful separation .
Dominique and Danielle ,
once one , would now stand each alone .
- Well , what do you think ? - That 's an extraordinary tape , Mr. McLennen .
Now , I tried to do a follow-up ,
but the institute was closed tome even as a friend of the twins .
- Why was that ? - Well , all I could find out at the time was that ...
after the operation there had been some complications .
- What sort of complications ? - I never did get any official information ,
so I slipped 20 bucks to one of the suture nurses , and she told me that ...
Dominique Blanchion had died on the operating table .
[ Engine Starting ]
[ Engine Cranking ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ People Chattering Indistinctly ]
[ Arguing ]
[ Woman Shouting ]
[ Woman Groaning ]
[ Screams , Moaning ]
[ Groaning , Moaning Stop ]
- [ Snap ] - [ Gasps ]
- What are you doing ? - I have my work to do .
[ Snapping Continues ]
- Do you live here ? - So they tell me .
Do you mind if I use your telephone ?
- No . - Where is it ?
It 's in the kitchen down the hall .
Thank you .
Better spray yourself , hon . You 're not supposed to be in here .
I 've got to use the telephone .
You 're not supposed to be in here .
[ Sniffs ] I think you have a cold .
No , no .
It 's a clean telephone .
Don 't just think you can walk in here like that .
Did you know that the germs can come through the wires ?
I never call and I never answer .
It 's a good way to get sick .
Very , very sick .
That 's how I got so sick . Someone called me on the telephone !
What 's going on here ? Who are you ?
My name is Grace Collier and I write for The Staten Island Panorama ,
- and I must use the telephone . - No !
[ Screaming ] No ! Don 't give it to her . Don 't !
She won 't use it , Arlene . She won 't .
Trust me .
[ Choked Sobs ]
Look , this is the Lynton Clinic . You can 't just come walking in here like this .
Well I can if one of your patients is roaming around loose murdering people .
Oh , come on . There have been a lot of wild rumors going around about us ,
but I wouldn 't expect the Panorama to take them seriously .
I take them seriously and I 'm going to call the police !
Better talk to the head of the clinic . Now , if you call about 10 : 00 tomorrow ...
I 'll speak to him now !
- I 'll see if he 'll see you . He 's probably gone to bed . - [ Moans ]
Hello , Doctor . I 'm sorry to disturb you .
There 's a girl here who says she 's a reporter from the Panorama .
She insists on talking to you .
Okay .
Doctor will be right with you . Arlene ...
- You did a good job cleaning up . - [ Sobbing ]
Now , you can take your things back to the supply room .
[ Exhales ] One of your patients is a murderess .
I followed her here tonight . Now , we 've got to call the police . That 's him !
Dr. Breton , this girl says she 's from the Panorama .
Hello , Margaret , why aren 't you in your room ?
This man is involved in a murder and we have got to call the police .
She came to us last night . We 're very happy to have her join our family .
Oh , I was off duty .
Margaret , this is Mr. Jansen . Margaret Grisham .
- Hello , Margaret . - Nice try .
If you 'll go and check my I.D. , it 's in my car outside .
I am Grace Collier .
I wouldn 't insist on " Margaret " right away . We want to respect your wishes .
When you 're ready to have us call you Margaret , you tell us .
- Take her to room 23 . - Right .
Dr. Corbin , prepare her for hypnotherapy .
Come with me , Margaret . Grace , I mean . It 's all right .
Please . Now , you 've got to believe me .
I am perfectly sane. just go downstairs and check my bag . It 's in my car .
- Yes , Grace. just as soon as you 're settled in . - No ! Now !
- I 'm afraid my life is in danger . - I understand .
Oh , God ! I know what that sounds like .
I 'm serious . As soon as you find out who I am ,
you 'll know that they are making all of this up !
Grace , I believe you 're serious in what you think .
- Let go of my arm ! - Well , it 's a little rough going here in the dark , Grace .
- Stop calling me Grace ! - Then , you really do want to be Margaret ?
No , damn it , my name is Grace !
Let go . Let go .
All right , Margaret , just push up your sleeve for me . This won 't hurt a bit .
- [ Screams ] Help ! - Get her in the room .
No ! [ Screams ]
[ Screaming ] Help !
[ Breton ] Open your eyes .
You came here to ask me questions .
- Is that correct ? - [ Grace ] Yes .
You will ask me questions . You will remember my answers exactly , word for word .
- Do you understand ? - Yes .
Good . Now , repeat after me .
What did you do with the body ?
- Repeat . - What did you do with the body ?
It was all a ridiculous mistake .
There was no body .
- Repeat . - It was all a ridiculous mistake .
There was no body , because there was no murder .
Repeat .
There was no body because there was no murder ...
- Again . - There was no body because there was no murder .
Good .
When you awaken , all you will remember is what I have told you ...
if anyone should ask .
- Do you understand ? - Yes .
Good .
Now , I 'm going to take you deeper ... into deeper sleep .
Relax . Breathe in .
Breathe out .
Breathe in .
Now , listen to me very carefully .
You came to watch us , to spy on us , to feed on our sorrows ...
look at me ... at no cost .
- Do you hear me ? - Yes , I hear you .
Good .
You want to know all our secrets ?
All right . We will share them with you .
Watch .
Wh-Why is she here ?
Don 't you remember ? She was always here .
Don 't you remember ?
- [ Danielle ] No . - [ Breton ] Go back .
- [ Danielle Murmuring ] - Go back . Remember .
- [ Danielle ] I can remember . - [ Breton ] Remember when you were very young .
[ Echoing ] I am in agreement with my colleagues .
Although they believe that Dominique ...
is the one who is truly disturbed ,
I think that they will find that Danielle , who is so sweet ,
so responsive , so normal ,
as opposed to her sister ,
can only be so because of her sister .
- Danielle ... - [ Danielle ] And the time we had the picnic .
- [ Breton ] That 's right , the picnic . - And people have come to see us .
- To see you , yes . - I remember .
- [ Breton ] What else do you remember ? - She is not just one .
- They were all my friends . - They were ... They were your friends .
- Oh , Dominique , it 's okay . - They brought ...
- Thank you , Charlie . - their picnic lunches ...
- and their cameras . - Yes .
And they brought their little children .
- Ah , yes . I remember that . - They gave you treats .
- Little cakes , candies ... - Yes , an apple ... You gave me an apple .
Apples , yes . And then they asked ...
- if they can take your picture . - Yes .
- Dominique didn 't like the children very much . - Is that right , Dominique ?
- No , she said that they were laughing at us . - Do you remember ?
- No , I can 't remember . - Go back . Try .
- What did they call you ? - I-l can 't remember that .
- Try to remember what they called you . - Go away , please !
- You can remember . You can remember . Look at me . - I can ? remember . No !
- Look at me ! - Go away ! I can ? remember that .
- You can remember . What did they call you ? - No . I don 't know !
- Remember ! - They said , " freak . " " Look at the freak . "
- [ Echoing ] the freak. the freak ... - Sweetie , smile .
- [ Echoing Continues ] ... the freak , the freak ... - [ Various Voices ] Smile .
[ Danielle ] Make them go away from me , please .
Don 't you remember what you learned last spring that you could never have ?
- No , I can 't remember . No , I can 't remember ! - Yes , you can . Try .
Don 't you remember you realized you could have no home ,
- no husband , no children , no baby ? - Yes , I remember that .
Yes , I remember that .
You 're supposed to be sleeping .
Why can 't you make her go away ?
Can you make her go away ? Please . Please .
Of course .
Help me . Don 't let him hurt me .
Help me . Help me .
- [ Sobbing ] - [ Breton ] Danielle , what happened afterward ?
[ Sobbing Continues ] I-I was walking in the garden ...
with Dominique and ...
I tried to tell her that I was going to have a baby .
And I ...
I tried to explain that it could be her baby too , but ...
but she doesn 't understand and she get very angry at me .
And she ... tried to kill the baby with the garden shear .
- Are you in pain ? - [ Sobbing ]
I 'm-I 'm going to lose my baby .
No , you will be fine .
- I 'm going to die . - Everything will be fine .
- [ Sobbing moaning ] - Everything will be fine . Everything will be fine .
Oh , it hurts me . Please help me .
[ Breton ] Do not be afraid . Do not be afraid .
Do not be afraid .
I am a surgeon . You have lost our baby .
You are bleeding very badly .
The only way I can save you is to separate you from Dominique .
- [ Danielle ] Am I going to die ? - No .
You will be fine . Everything will be fine .
Sleep . Sleep . Sleep .
[ Shrieks ]
[ Hysterical Screaming ]
Relax , relax , relax , relax .
- [ Screams Subside ] - [ Danielle Babbling ]
- Relax . Sleep . Sleep . Sleep . - [ Babbling Continues ]
- I-I am sure you 've come back , Dominique . - [ Groans ]
- Dominique ! Dominique . - Dominique is dead .
Please come back , Dominique .
Dominique is dead . Remember .
No , she 's not dead . She 's going to kill you .
- She " is " dead . - No !
- I know she 's not . No ! No , she 's not . - Sleep .
- Sleep . Sleep . Sleep . Sleep . - No . No ...
- She 's not . - Dominique is dead . She is dead .
Time you learn to accept her death .
We both have to go away now .
Danielle , I 'm going to marry you .
Do you remember ? How we came here to the clinic ...
and made it our own ?
It was good for a while .
But Dominique never died for you .
You kept her alive in your mind .
Sometimes ... Sometimes , you even became her ...
to reassure yourself of her existence .
You could never accept the guilt ,
The terrible guilt for Dominique 's death .
It was hard for me to accept what had happened ...
- that we could never live together as rnan and wife . - [ Murmurs ]
Every time I made love to you ,
Dominique came back ...
and took control of you .
I did not know how to rid you of her .
All I could do was give you the pills ...
and keep you sedated ...
until she went away .
- [ Moans ] - I tried to warn you about Dominique .
Dominique is dangerous for both of us .
To Dominique ,
any man that made love to you is me ...
Emil .
[ Sobbing ] Danielle ? Danielle ? I love you .
- [ Meaning ] - Look at this knife .
Look at it . You killed a man with this knife .
- Remember . Remember . - [ Moaning ]
- Remember . That 's it . - [ Groaning ]
- What happened ? - There was a cake .
A cake ? What else ?
They had candles .
Yes . What did you do ?
- I made a wish , - Yes .
- And I blew out the candles . - Yes .
And then I cut him !
[ Gasps ]
Relax , fellas . He 's dead .
[ Woman Weeping ]
just a minute , Mrs. Breton .
Are you prepared to confess to the murder of your husband Emil Breton ?
I warn you that whatever you say may be used as evidence against you .
I have never hurt anyone in my life .
You claim that you had a sister who did it ?
My sister died last spring .
Dawson .
- Well , Miss Collier , up and about ? - [ Chuckles ]
- How do you feel today ? - Oh , fine . Thanks .
- Oh , thank you for the chocolates . - Oh , you 're welcome .
- Would you like one ? - No , thank you .
Well , you 'll be interested to know that we 're reopening the whole case .
We already got her on first-degree murder for Breton .
But we haven 't had any luck turning up that black man you saw her slice up .
Now , I want you to tell me everything you can remember .
It was all a ridiculous mistake . There was no body .
Look , I apologize for having been so skeptical .
I should have put more trust in your claim .
It-It was all a ridiculous mistake .
What else do you want me to do ? Apologize in print ?
- I sent you candy . - I 'm telling you all I can remember !
Look , I talked to your editor , and he told rne about the detective that you hired .
What did he think ? I got a witness who saw the couch loaded onto the truck .
Now , obviously the body was hidden inside that couch .
Otherwise , why would they move it ?
It 's really quite simple . There was no body because there was no murder !
What was simple ? There 's nothing simple about any of this .
I-I just don 't understand you . Now you claim that there wasn 't a body .
If there wasn 't a body , why did you make such an accusation ?
You know how serious that could be ?
Grace has never deliberately told a lie in her life .
You have to understand that she 's not quite herself .
I 'm fine ! There 's absolutely nothing wrong with me !
All I know is there was no body because there was no murder !
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
[ Engine Off ]
[ Moos ]